http://www.karlshamns.com/about-us/data-privacy-information/

Available jobs
General Applications (Submit CV)
Data Privacy Information
You are here:
You are here:Data privacy information
AAK AB (publ.) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy, and we will always aim to protect your personal data in an appropriate manner with adherence to applicable Data Protection Privacy Laws.
Below, you will find information what type of personal data we collect and how we process such data and your rights against us as an individual.
AAK AB (publ.), Reg. No. 556669-2850, with its principal address Skrivaregatan 9, 215 32, Malmö, Sweden, is regarded the controller for the personal data we collect and process.
AAK AB has appointed a Personal Data Officer to ensure that we continuously handle your personal data in an open, accurate and legal manner. You can contact our personal data representative at DPO@aak.com.
What type of information we collect
AAK mainly collect and process personal data that you provided to us in connection with your business relations with AAK, such as your name, title and contact details. Personal data may also from time-to-time be collected from publicly available sources, such as company websites, business publications, and trade fairs and similar.
AAK also collects personal data which you voluntarily submit when applying for a job; name, contact details, CV’s, resumes and cover letters.
When you request to receive newsletters, marketing and promotional material, general information or wish to connect with us online, we may (depending on type of contact you request) collect the following personally identifiable information about you e.g., contact details (e-mail, address, phone, professional title or role), company name and language preferences.
How do we handle personal data?
Personal data is processed in order for us to conduct our business operations and to maintain contacts with our business contacts, partners, suppliers and for direct marketing purposes. Personal data may also be used to send out press releases, financial reports, invitations to seminars and similar events.
When connecting with us for business, by general contact requests, by registration as a recipient of our subscription services or to download or request marketing material from us, you will be asked to give your consent to our processing of your personal information for this purpose. We will use your information for marketing and market research, such as if we think one of our products, services, or offers may interest you, or those of our third party partners, we or they may contact you about them by email, SMS, on the phone, post or through other means of communications. All of our marketing communications will include the option to unsubscribe from us contacting you again.
When applying for a job on our online portal we rely on our legitimate interest to process your application and the personal data you submit, and your consent to store your application data and to contact you for future job opportunities.
For other types of processing, we generally rely on our legitimate interest to store and process your data, because we have a strong interest in being able to do conduct and maintain our business with you and the companies and organizations that you represent. We will not share your personal data to third parties except in the following circumstances;
(i) if we have obtained your consent to do so,
(ii) in order to comply with legal obligations or defending against legal claims,
(iii) with other legal entities or suppliers we work with that provide services;
(iv) to other subsidiaries within AAK AB group.
We do not sell any personal data to third parties. We generally only process your personal information within the EU/EEA. Should personal data be transferred outside EU/EEA, such transfers shall be in accordance with applicable Data Protection Laws and require the
receiving entity, if located in a country outside EU/EEA, to have adequate levels of data protection and safeguards in place.
How long do we store your personal data?
We retain your personal data according to our retention policy and in accordance with our obligations under applicable law. Under our retention policy we only retain data for as long as relevant to initiate, maintain or administer our business relationship with you, the company or organization that you represent.
You may at any time unsubscribe from services you have requested from us, including our subscription services and/or receiving marketing material. If you unsubscribe, your details will no longer be saved for this purpose.
Personal data processed for recruitment purposes will be processed and stored until the position is closed and up to two years after, in order to defend against potential legal claims. Data stored for future job opportunities is subject to your consent and stored for period of 3 years for this purpose. You may at any time withdraw your consent for this purpose and have your data deleted upon request.
Your Rights related to our processing of your personal data
You have the right to request confirmation whether we process personal data relating to you and where we process personal data about you. Further you have the right to request access to what information we have about you. If the personal data we currently hold or process about you is incorrect or inadequate, you are entitled to request your data to be corrected or supplemented.
Under certain circumstances you may also have the right to request that your personal data is deleted or object to having your personal data processed. Please note, that these rights are not absolute, and we may have a right to deny your request where we have compelling interest to do so. Under certain conditions you may also request that get your personal data transferred in electronic format.
Before responding to a request, we have a legitimate interest to ensure the authenticity of your request and identity. Please provide proper documentation or other means to verify your identity together with your request.
If you believe we processed your personal information in violation of applicable Data Protection laws, please raise your concerns with us, or you may file a complaint with the Swedish Data Protection Authority who is the relevant supervising authority. Further instructions can be found on the Data Protection Authority website, www.datainspektionen.se.
Please note, that there is always a risk of disclosing personal data, regardless of that personally, by phone or over the internet, and that no technology system can be completely protected from intrusion. However, AKK always makes every effort to take appropriate technical measures to prevent and minimize the risks of unauthorized use access to, improper use or corruption of your personal data.
Miscellaneous
This information is subject to regular review and AAK reserves the right to revise the content of this information from time to time. If any part herein is inconsistent with applicable law, not applicable or for some reason cannot be maintained, however, other parts will not be affected in any way.
Contact us
If you have any questions or comments about the content of this information or if you want to rely on any of your rights as described above, you are welcome to contact us at gdpr@aak.com or contact our appointed DPO directly at DPO@aak.com.
Learn more
Terms and conditions
Access to and use of this AAK AB site is subject to the following terms and conditions and the laws of Sweden.
Cookies
We use cookies to give you the best experience when visiting our website.
Falkland Islands (Malvinas)
Holy See (Vatican City State)
Virgin Islands, U.S.
